clicktime.com 2019-05-16

# Privacy | ClickTime Web Timesheet

## ClickTime is committed to your privacy

The developers of ClickTime have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to the protection of your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices.

## Introduction

Content and information submitted by users to ClickTime is referred to in this policy as " **Customer Data** ". Customer Data is controlled by the organization or other third party that purchased the ClickTime services (the " **Customer** "). Where ClickTime collects or processes Customer Data, it does so on behalf of the Customer.

If you are using ClickTime by invitation of a Customer, whether that Customer is your employer, another organization, or an individual, you are an "End-user." That Customer is the sole owner of the data submitted to ClickTime.

## Information Collected

**Account and Registration Information** : We ask for and may collect personal information about you such as your name, address, phone number, email address, and credit card information, as well as certain related information like your company name when you register for an account or utilize ClickTime.

If you sign-up for a free trial Account, you are not required to enter your credit card information unless and until you decide to continue with a paid subscription to our services. A third-party intermediary is used to manage credit card processing. This intermediary is not permitted to store, retain, or use your billing information for any purpose except for credit card processing on our behalf.

We refer to any information described above as “Account Information” for the purposes of this Policy. By voluntarily providing us with **Account Information** , you represent that you are the owner of such personal data or otherwise have the requisite consent to provide it to us.

**Services Usage Information** : This is information about how you are accessing and using the services, which may include administrative and support communications with us, information about account configuration, custom fields, and preferences.

**Contact Information** : With your permission, any contact information you choose to import (manually or otherwise).

**Device Information** : When you download and use our services, we automatically collect information on the type of device and operating system version you use.

## Use and Disclosure

When you complete one of our online forms, such as a registration or marketing form, it is required that you provide contact information (such as your name, email address, address, company name, role, etc.). We use your contact information from these forms to:

  * Send you information so that you may access demo accounts and set up a ClickTime account.
  * Contact you when necessary, such as to notify you of an expired account or for customer services.
  * Provide additional information about ClickTime's services, partners, promotions, and events, via email, postal mail, or phone.
  * Create invoices for ClickTime usage.

Our computer system uses your email address as your unique login name and to automatically send you your password if you use the "Forgot my Password" function. Your password is hashed and not knowable to anyone other than you, so we cannot and will not share your password information with anyone. When we collect your personal information, that information is for ClickTime's use alone, except:

  * When we have your express permission
  * To our authorized distributors or resellers, who may provide sales and support functions to your geographical area or specific industry
  * To providers of our critical systems infrastructure, as described in our sub-processors list
  * When law enforcement requires it
  * If you violate our Terms of Service or our rights and property

Except as disclosed in this paragraph, **third parties will neither be granted your personal information nor will your information ever be sold**. At our discretion based on your industry or location, we may provide your contact information to an authorized distributor of ClickTime who has contractually agreed to abide by these privacy policies. Otherwise, any information shared with third parties will be shared as aggregate statistics. ClickTime offers you a choice in the way we use provided information. If you would like to change the way that information is received from ClickTime, go to our Unsubscribe Form and enter your email address to opt-out of receiving future emails. ClickTime is an online, hosted application. On certain occasions, ClickTime may need to notify you of important announcements in regards to the operation of our services. These announcements may be sent regardless of your opt-out status, and your only mechanism to avoid these notices is to cease your use of the ClickTime services. 

When an individual customer's administrator enrolls a new user in ClickTime, that administrator may elect to enter certain personal details. This data is considered application data and is not used by ClickTime in any way, other than when ClickTime itself sends important system notices to all users or as described in our sub-processors list. For application data (generally timesheet and expense data) which is entered by end-users themselves, ClickTime considers this data to be proprietary to each customer and ClickTime will not disclose this information except: 

  * When retrieved by members of your own ClickTime account whom you have configured for access (for example, your designated ClickTime account Administrator)
  * When we have the customer’s or end-user’s express permission (for example, if we need the assistance of a third party to assist you with technical support.)
  * When we are compelled to by law enforcement or a court order from any competent jurisdiction where we conduct business

## Cookies Policy

ClickTime uses cookies to provide and support our website and Services, as explained in our Cookie Policy.

## Publicity

By using the ClickTime services, you grant ClickTime the right to list your "company" or "entity" name on our customer list, which may appear in our marketing materials. Individuals will not be listed, nor will we will list any specific information about your account. You may request to be removed from this list at any time. In addition, we may ask for your permission to list your name and a statement about ClickTime among our customer testimonials. If you grant us this permission, your name and comment will appear among other customer testimonials. 

## Security

We utilize industry standard methods to protect all data shared with ClickTime. Personal information shared through our marketing site is stored securely by us. Data submitted to the ClickTime App (your contact and time tracking information) are visible only by your company's administrator(s) and are not available to any other users or non-users of ClickTime (website and App), except in cases where our technical support team provides assistance to you and obtains your permission to access this information.

Although we are not responsible if a third party accesses your information by breaching our security measures, we will inform you of such event within 72 hours, as directed in the General Protection Data Regulation. You can learn more about our Security Practices here.

## Privacy Shield - for EU Customers Only

ClickTime complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. ClickTime has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, ClickTime commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact ClickTime at: [privacy@clicktime.com](mailto:privacy@clicktime.com). ClickTime has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield> for more information or to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. **U.S. Federal Trade Commission enforcement** : ClickTime's commitments under the Privacy Shield are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the United States Federal Trade Commission. **Inquiries and complaints** : If you believe ClickTime maintains your personal data in one of the services within the scope of our Privacy Shield certification, you may direct any inquiries or complaints concerning our Privacy Shield compliance to [privacy@clicktime.com](mailto:privacy@clicktime.com). ClickTime will respond within 45 days. If we fail to respond within that time, or if our response does not address your concern, you may contact JAMS, which provides an independent third-party dispute resolution body based in the United States, [here](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield). JAMS has committed to respond to complaints and to provide appropriate recourse at no cost to you. If neither ClickTime nor JAMS resolves your complaint, you may have the possibility to engage in binding arbitration through the Privacy Shield Panel. **Third parties who may receive personal data** : ClickTime uses a limited number of third-party services providers to assist us in providing our services to customers. These third party providers offer customer support to our customers, perform database monitoring and other technical operations, assist with the transmission of data, and provide data storage services. These third parties may access, process, or store personal data in the course of providing their services. ClickTime maintains contracts with these third parties restricting their access, use and disclosure of personal data in compliance with our Privacy Shield obligations, and ClickTime may be liable if they fail to meet those obligations and we are responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

## Children’s Information

The ClickTime Services are not directed to children under 16. If you learn that a child under 16 has provided us with personal information without consent, please contact [privacy@clicktime.com](mailto:privacy@clicktime.com). 

## Correct/Update

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact [privacy@clicktime.com](mailto:privacy@clicktime.com) or mail us at: ClickTime Customer services clicktime.com, Inc. 282 Second Street, 4th Floor San Francisco, CA 94105. 

## Amendments

Our site contains links to a number of websites that may offer useful information to our visitors. This Website Privacy Statement does not apply to those sites, and we recommend communicating with them directly for information on their privacy policies. 

Any changes to this policy will be posted at this URL and will be effective when posted. Please check back periodically if you have any concerns about changes made to our Privacy Policy. 

_Revised: April 23, 2018_
